Inventory to the Annelise Graebner Anderson Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Office of Management and Budget, 1981-1983 (Box 28-139)
  - Note on justice – maintenance of funding levels for law enforcement (Box-folder 138: 8)
  - Memorandum from Mike Hudson regarding the Senate (Box-folder 138: 9)
  - Phil Winn – November 19, 1983 (Box-folder 138: 10)
  - List of attendees for meeting, Wednesday, March 10 at 3 P.M. in Jim Baker’s office (Box-folder 138: 11)
  - Table of contents – program supplementals/pay supplementals/budget amendments (Box-folder 138: 12)
  - Note to Annelise Anderson regarding the immigration bill, the Commerce, State, Justice bill, and BRB papers for DAS’ use – December 8, 1982 (Box-folder 138: 13)
  - FY 1985 – Spring Review – Child Program (Box-folder 139: 1-2)
  - Bill Introduction Status Report – May 8, 1981 (Box-folder 139: 3)
  - Status of Legislative Proposals in Support of Budget Savings (Box-folder 139: 4)
  - Additional HR 6100 materials (Box-folder 139: 5)
  - Markup notes – 1981 supplementals, rescissions, and deferrals – Subcommittee on transportation and related agencies – Senator Mark Andrews, Chairman (Box-folder 139: 6)
  - Bill Introduction Status Report – April 28, 1981 (Box-folder 139: 7)
  - Analysis of House Budget Committee Chairman’s Proposals on Non-Program Budget Reductions: Quick and Detailed Responses (Box-folder 139: 8)
  - Status of Administration Legislative Proposals (Box-folder 139: 9)
  - Noon April 2 Update of Legislative Status (Box-folder 139: 10)
  - Bill Introduction Status Report – March 13, 1981 (Box-folder 139: 11)
  - Supplemental views of representatives Delbert L. Latta, Ralph Regula, Bud Shuster, Bill Frenzel, Jack Kemp, James G. Martin, Paul Trible, Ed Bethune, Lynn Martin, Albert Lee Smith, Jr., Eugene Johnston, Bobbi Fielder (Box-folder 139: 12)
- Files regarding book, Thinking About America: United States in the 1990s, 1987-1989 (Box 140-144)
  - Copy for brochure, 1988 (Box-folder 140: 1)
  - Brochure for 1990s project (Box-folder 140: 2)
  - Copies of photos used for brochure, 1988 (Box-folder 140: 3)
  - News Clips, 1988 (Box-folder 140: 4)
  - Publicity file, 1988 (Box-folder 140: 5)
  - Intro drafts (Box-folder 140: 6)
  - Klatzkin, Amy resume, 1987 (Box-folder 140: 7)
  - Proposal for 1990s book, 1988 (Box-folder 140: 8)
  - Contributions, 1987 (Box-folder 140: 9)
  - Contracts for 1990s book (Box-folder 140: 10)
  - Blurbs, 1988 (Box-folder 140: 11)
  - General correspondence, 1988 (Box-folder 140: 12)
  - Reagan remarks at Hoover Dinner, 1988 (Box-folder 140: 13)
  - Book Party, 1988 (Box-folder 140: 14)
  - 1990s book orders, 1988 (Box-folder 140: 15)
  - Ads for the 90s book, 1988 (Box-folder 140: 16)
  - Miller III, James C., 1989 (Box-folder 140: 17)
  - Friedman, Milton, 1988 (Box-folder 140: 18)
  - Shultz, George P., 1988 (Box-folder 140: 19)
  - Roger Robinson (Box-folder 140: 20)
  - Hook, Sidney, 1988 (Box-folder 140: 21-22)
  - Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr, 1988 (Box-folder 140: 23-24)
  - Teller, Edward, 1988 (Box-folder 141: 1-2)
  - Wessen, Robert, 1988 (Box-folder 141: 3-4)
  - Staar, Richard F., 1988 (Box-folder 141: 5-6)
  - Stockdale, James B., 1988 (Box-folder 141: 7-8)
  - Reagan, Ronald, 1988 (Box-folder 141: 9-10)
  - Rosenberg, Nathan, 1988 (Box-folder 141: 11-12)
  - Sowell, Thomas, 1988 (Box-folder 142: 1-2)
  - Nixon, Richard, 1988 (Box-folder 142: 3-4)
  - O'Neill, June, 1988 (Box-folder 142: 5-6)
  - advertising in reply, 1989 (Box-folder 142: 7)
  - Public Affairs Ideas, 1989 (Box-folder 142: 8)
  - book jacket copy (Box-folder 142: 9)
  - book jacket ads (Box-folder 142: 10)
  - Ads for the 90s book (Box-folder 142: 11-12)
  - copies of letters to W. Glenn Campbell, 1989 (Box-folder 142: 13)
  - Book blurbs, 1988 (Box-folder 143: 1)
  - reprints, 1989 (Box-folder 143: 2)
  - Letters to Annelise Anderson, 1988 (Box-folder 143: 3)
  - Copies of letters to Dennis L. Bark, 1988 (Box-folder 143: 4)
  - Copies of letters to Ronald J. Getz, 1988 (Box-folder 143: 5)
  - Lou Xinyue, 1989 (Box-folder 143: 6)
  - Eva Mae Perakis, 1989 (Box-folder 143: 7)
  - award, 1989 (Box-folder 143: 8)
  - United States Information Agency, 1989 (Box-folder 143: 9)
  - Alumni conference, 1989 (Box-folder 143: 10)
  - Op-Eds, 1988 (Box-folder 143: 11)
  - Ford, Gerald, 1988 (Box-folder 143: 12-13)
  - Haselkorn, Avigdor, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 143: 14-15)
  - Hayek, F. A., 1988 (Box-folder 143: 16-17)
  - Inman, Bobby R., 1988 (Box-folder 143: 18-19)
  - Johnson, D. Gale, 1988 (Box-folder 144: 1-2)
  - Carter, Jimmy, 1988 (Box-folder 144: 3-4)
  - Moore, Thomas G., 1988 (Box-folder 144: 5-6)
  - Kirkpatrick, Jeane J., 1987 (Box-folder 144: 7)
  - Krauss, Melvyn B., 1988 (Box-folder 144: 8-9)
  - Meese, Edwin, 1988 (Box-folder 144: 10-11)
  - Interviews done, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 144: 12)
  - 1990s Progress/ To Do, 1989 (Box-folder 144: 13)
  - Themes 1990s (Box-folder 144: 14)
- Hoover TV facility Station materials, 1984-1990 (Box 145-146)
  - Stories, 1988 (Box-folder 145: 1)
  - Review Copies/ Reviews, 1989 (Box-folder 145: 2)
  - Presentation Materials, 1988 (Box-folder 145: 3)
  - Permissions, 1989 (Box-folder 145: 4)
  - Press - The Tide in Affairs of Men, 1989 (Box-folder 145: 5)
  - PAT/ Offprints, 1988 (Box-folder 145: 6)
  - Dennis L. Bark, 1987 (Box-folder 145: 7)
  - Social Security Administration 1989 Annual Report to the Congress (Box-folder 145: 8)
  - Copy of drafts and final, 1985 (Box-folder 145: 9)
  - Alumni Center Campbell Draft, 1989 (Box-folder 145: 10)
  - Blurbs, 1988 (Box-folder 145: 11)
  - Conference Alums, 1988 (Box-folder 145: 12-13)
  - Stanford Magazine (Box-folder 145: 14)
  - HIP McCarthy manuscript Terms for Soviet Access to Western Computer Technology (Box-folder 145: 15)
  - Public Affairs - Letter to G. Walker from Jim Risser/ Knight Fellowship, 1989 (Box-folder 145: 16)
  - Public Affairs/ AA memo regarding Mailing Lists, 1989 (Box-folder 145: 17)
  - Articles about Hoover and Hoover scholars (Box-folder 145: 18)
  - Larry Diamond Research outline/proposal, 1990 (Box-folder 145: 19)
  - Memo to A. Codevilla regarding students from People's Republic of China, 1989 (Box-folder 145: 20)
  - Press publications, 1989 (Box-folder 145: 21)
  - Director's intro to new budget note on RTC and Working Capital (Box-folder 145: 22)
  - TV, 1989 (Box-folder 145: 23)
  - Kamenev, Valentin, 1990 (Box-folder 145: 24)
  - Video Archives memo to Charles Palm, 1989 (Box-folder 146: 1)
  - Electronic Bulletin Boards, memo to R. Myers, 1989 (Box-folder 146: 2)
  - Television Thieriot, P.E., 1989 (Box-folder 146: 3)
  - Satellite Demonstration, 1989 (Box-folder 146: 4)
  - Brisley, Denny, 1989 (Box-folder 146: 5)
  - Hoover Satellite Television Facilities, 1989 (Box-folder 146: 6-7)
  - Television, 1984 (Box-folder 146: 8)
  - Stanford Instructional Television Network, 1988 (Box-folder 146: 9)
  - Allgyer, Warren, 1989 (Box-folder 146: 10)
  - Satellite TV draft materials, 1988 (Box-folder 146: 11)
  - TV Expenses, 1989 (Box-folder 146: 12)
  - Memo of Television agreement between Stanford Instructional Television Network and Hoover, 1989 (Box-folder 146: 13)
  - Television consultant billing, 1990 (Box-folder 146: 14)
  - TV Project expenses, 1990 (Box-folder 146: 15)
  - TV/miscellaneous correspondence, 1989 (Box-folder 146: 16)
  - incoming correspondence, 1989 (Box-folder 146: 17)
  - Raisian, John, 1989 (Box-folder 146: 18)
  - John Raisian Board Memos, 1989 (Box-folder 146: 19)
  - Hoover Institution Television Facilities, 1989 (Box-folder 146: 20)
  - Memos regarding television project and quotes from Edward Teller, 1989 (Box-folder 146: 21)
  - Teller documentary and Cold Fusion Notes, 1989 (Box-folder 146: 22-23)
  - Weekend extra (Box-folder 146: 24)
  - Excerpts (Box-folder 146: 25)
  - Hoover Satellite Television Facilities, 1989 (Box-folder 146: 26)
  - Signed facilities request form, 1989 (Box-folder 146: 27)
  - Television - BizNet Broadcast facilities rate card, 1988 (Box-folder 146: 28)
- Incremental sound recordings, 1954, 1961
  - Speeches at Better Business Relations meetings, 1.0 sound tape reel (Tape Cabinet)
    Scope and Contents note
    Part 1: "The Art of Listening" by Dr. Ralph Nichols - President of the University of Minnesota. Speaking at convention of Better Business Bureau People at Gearhart, Oregon around May/June 1960. (Sponsored by Chamber of Commerce?)
    Part 2: "Encroaching Control" by Ronald Reagan. Speech at the 10th annual Better Business Relations conference, September 25, 1961.
    A talk on the threat of communism in the United States. Reagan concentrates on how trends and events of the recent pass point to a passive encroachment of communism. He argues communist control is akin to a fire by arson or accident, that the end result is the same.
    Access
    Use copy reference number: 90032_a_0012963
  - Prisoner of War radio interviews, 1954; 1.0 discs (Record-cabinet Record Cabinet)
    Transcribed radio interviews with Ronald Reagan, Nancy Davis, and Capt. Robert H. Wise for "Prisoner of War" with commentary by Dick Simmons. 2 copies, each one disc in extent.
    Use copy reference number: 90032_a_0000672
  - The Republic for Which It Stands / Key to Victory, 1961; 1.0 discs (Record-cabinet Record Cabinet)
    "The Republic for Which It Stands," narrated by Ronald Reagan backed with "Key to Victory," narrated by Dick Gordon, sound vinyl disc.
  - John Noble and Ronald Reagan speeches, 1963 June 6
- Digital files, 2005-2008
  Includes 47 WAV or MP3 content files of recordings of an Annelise Anderson interview of Michael Novak, a Ronald Reagan speech from late 1964 or early 1965 as it appears to be a speech he gave after Goldwater's defeat to Johnson, and recordings of "Hollywood Profile" radio program with host Ronald Reagan, made from LP discs. All recordings digitized by Hoover staff from original LP discs retained by Annelise Anderson.